<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DjangoCon on Mariatta</title><link>https://mariatta.ca/tags/djangocon/</link><description>Recent content in DjangoCon on Mariatta</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 17:07:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mariatta.ca/tags/djangocon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ice Cream Selfie @ DjangoCon US 2018</title><link>https://mariatta.ca/posts/ice_cream_selfies/2018/djangoconus_2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 17:07:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://mariatta.ca/posts/ice_cream_selfies/2018/djangoconus_2018/</guid><description>Hammond&amp;rsquo;s Gourmet Ice Cream It was fun visiting San Diego for DjangoCon US 2018. I gave my talk Don&amp;rsquo;t Be a Robot; Build the Bot. I think it was well received 😊
This was also a special travel trip, because, well it happens that my husband also needed to travel for work at the same time, so we don&amp;rsquo;t have anyone to look after our two kids. I ended up taking my kids with me to the conference.</description></item><item><title>Ice Cream Selfie @ DjangoCon Europe, PyCon Italy 2017</title><link>https://mariatta.ca/posts/ice_cream_selfies/2017/pyconit_djangoconeu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 16:02:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://mariatta.ca/posts/ice_cream_selfies/2017/pyconit_djangoconeu/</guid><description>Hero image photo by Bartek Pawlik, DjangoCon Europe.
Icy Dot Wine I was just walking around in Florence, having given my talk at two conferences in the same week: PyCon Italy and DjangoCon Europe 2017.
At that time, Ice cream selfie isn&amp;rsquo;t quite a ritual yet, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know which shop this was.
After many years, I tracked down the shop name! This was from Icy Dot Wine.</description></item><item><title>Ice Cream Selfie @ DjangoCon US 2016</title><link>https://mariatta.ca/posts/ice_cream_selfies/2016/djangoconus_2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 16:02:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://mariatta.ca/posts/ice_cream_selfies/2016/djangoconus_2016/</guid><description>Capogiro Gelato Artisans My first ever conference talk, and my first ever Ice Cream Selfie! The rest is history.
Trio Gelato from Capogiro Gelato: Cappucino, Pistachio, and Bacio.
While my public speaking and ice cream selfies continues, sadly Capogiro Gelato Artisans has since closed down. 😢</description></item></channel></rss>