<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mariatta</title>
    <link>https://mariatta.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mariatta</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mariatta.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Greeting! This is an introduction post. This post tests the followings:
Hero image is in the same directory as the post. This post should be at top of the sidebar. Post author should be the same as specified in author.yaml file. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Samples</title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/posts/markdown-sample/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/posts/markdown-sample/</guid>
      <description>This is a sample post intended to test the followings:
A different post author. Table of contents. Markdown content rendering. Math rendering. Emoji rendering. Markdown Syntax Rendering Headings The following HTML &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;—&amp;lt;h6&amp;gt; elements represent six levels of section headings. &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt; is the highest section level while &amp;lt;h6&amp;gt; is the lowest.
H1 H2 H3 H4 H5 H6 Paragraph Xerum, quo qui aut unt expliquam qui dolut labo. Aque venitatiusda cum, voluptionse latur sitiae dolessi aut parist aut dollo enim qui voluptate ma dolestendit peritin re plis aut quas inctum laceat est volestemque commosa as cus endigna tectur, offic to cor sequas etum rerum idem sintibus eiur?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Content</title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/posts/category/sub-category/rich-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/posts/category/sub-category/rich-content/</guid>
      <description>This sample post tests the followings:
Category, sub-category nesting in the sidebar. Hero image and other images are in images folder inside this post directory. Different media rendering like image, tweet, YouTube video, Vimeo video etc. Image Sample Tweet Sample Owl bet you&amp;#39;ll lose this staring contest 🦉 pic.twitter.com/eJh4f2zncC
&amp;mdash; San Diego Zoo Wildlife Alliance (@sandiegozoo) October 26, 2021 YouTube Video Sample Vimeo Video Sample </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcodes Samples</title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/posts/shortcodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/posts/shortcodes/</guid>
      <description>This is a sample post intended to test the followings:
Default hero image. Different shortcodes. Alert The following alerts are available in this theme.
This is sample alert with type=&amp;quot;success&amp;quot;. This is sample alert with type=&amp;quot;danger&amp;quot;. This is sample alert with type=&amp;quot;warning&amp;quot;. This is sample alert with type=&amp;quot;info&amp;quot;. This is sample alert with type=&amp;quot;dark&amp;quot;. This is sample alert with type=&amp;quot;primary&amp;quot;. This is sample alert with type=&amp;quot;secondary&amp;quot;. Image A sample image without any attribute.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>aaaa</title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/notes/talk_abstracts/api_for_that/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/notes/talk_abstracts/api_for_that/</guid>
      <description>{{ }}
Talk Abstract hahahaha
{{ }}
{{ }}
blablabla {{ }}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Unit Testing and Continuous Integration</title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/notes/talk_abstracts/intro_to_unit_test_and_ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/notes/talk_abstracts/intro_to_unit_test_and_ci/</guid>
      <description>Intro to Unit Testing and Continuous Integration Talk Abstract Having unit tests and continuous integration (CI) as part of your development are considered best practises. But how do these things work? In this talk, we will cover the benefits of writing unit tests and how to get started with it in Python. Then, we&amp;rsquo;ll step it up running tests as part CI. And that&amp;rsquo;s not all! CI is not just about running tests, but for other things as well, like code quality checks, and even building and generating documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PEP Talk</title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/notes/talk_abstracts/pep_talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/notes/talk_abstracts/pep_talk/</guid>
      <description>PEP Talk Talk Abstract If you use Python, chances are you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of PEP 8, the Python style guide.
But do you know what PEPs really are? PEPs are more than just a style guide. A PEP stands for Python Enhancement Proposal. It&amp;rsquo;s a proposal documentation for when you want to change the Python programming language in a big way, for example when you want to change the syntax of Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker Bio</title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/notes/speaker_assets/speaker_bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/notes/speaker_assets/speaker_bio/</guid>
      <description>Speaker Bio Mariatta is a Python core developer where she focuses on improving the workflow and documentation. She is active in the Python community as an advisor for the Global PyLadies, co-founder of PyCascades, and is currently chairing PyCon US conference.
For her contributions to the Python and community, she received the PSF Community Service Award in 2018 and Google Open Source Peer Bonus Award in 2017 and 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker Headshot</title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/notes/speaker_assets/speaker_headshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/notes/speaker_assets/speaker_headshot/</guid>
      <description> Headshot You can use the following headshot as my speaker profile. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mariatta.ca/posts/category/blabla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mariatta.ca/posts/category/blabla/</guid>
      <description>Abstract If you use Python, chances are you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of PEP 8, the Python style guide.
But do you know what PEPs really are? PEPs are more than just a style guide. A PEP stands for Python Enhancement Proposal. It&amp;rsquo;s a proposal documentation for when you want to change the Python programming language in a big way, for example when you want to change the syntax of Python. Think of the addition of f-strings, the walrus operator, or the ExceptionGroup, those changes all started with a PEP.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
