<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>mariatta.ca - conference</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://mariatta.ca/feeds/conference.tag.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://mariatta.ca/</id><updated>2019-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Mariatta @ PyCon 2019 Recap</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/mariatta-pycon-2019-recap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mariatta</name></author><id>tag:mariatta.ca,2019-05-15:/mariatta-pycon-2019-recap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was at PyCon from April 29 - May 7. It's my fifth PyCon US. It's been a memorable
and, I kept busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5fCBZxXsAAnVU3.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a number of pre-planned activities for PyCon, like running the language
summit, giving talks, tutorial, etc. Thought I'll share a quick summary of how
they all …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was at PyCon from April 29 - May 7. It's my fifth PyCon US. It's been a memorable
and, I kept busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5fCBZxXsAAnVU3.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a number of pre-planned activities for PyCon, like running the language
summit, giving talks, tutorial, etc. Thought I'll share a quick summary of how
they all went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="zapier-pycon-2019"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Zapier &amp;#64; PyCon 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D52HmedWsAAr3D2.jpg:medium" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm one of 14 Zapiens at PyCon 2019. I staffed Zapier's booth on Friday and Saturday.
We had socks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="python-language-summit-2019"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Python Language Summit 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The language summit was a success. First of all, we were able to stay somewhat
on time, which I'm personally quite happy about. Other thing to be proud of,
it was the most diverse audience I've seen. Our audience consists of, not just long-time
Python core developers, but also new contributors as well as members from
the wider Python ecosystem, such as from Twisted, Django, and BeeWare project.
We had talks about circuit Python, team communication, and mentorship. I personally
think all the talks were very interesting and refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've invited A. Jesse Jiryu Davis to cover the event. You can see his posts
at The PSF's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pyfound.blogspot.com/2019/05/the-2019-python-language-summit.html"&gt;official blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We forgot to take a group photo after the summit!! 😱 but we had a group photo
with PyCon staff ... (image from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pystar/status/1123782745585483776"&gt;PyCon's twitter account&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5hQscyW0AEIjUs.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pep-581"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PEP 581&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the topic of discussion was &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0581/"&gt;PEP 581&lt;/a&gt;.
Since Jesse is writing up the post about it, I won't duplicate the effort.
But you can see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/mariatta/pep-581"&gt;my slides here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd really like to see us making progress with this before the next Python
Language Summit. There were lots of action items, and things we still need
to figure out, but those will be addressed in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0588/"&gt;PEP 588&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to update PEP 588 with the items raised during the language summit,
I really haven't had much time to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hands-on-intro-to-aiohttp"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hands-on Intro to aiohttp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Svetlov and I gave a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us-pycon-2019-tutorial.readthedocs.io/"&gt;beginner tutorial to aiohttp&lt;/a&gt;.
Our tutorial material is available online, and licensed under CC-BY-SA 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew is the maintainer of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.aiohttp.org/en/stable/"&gt;aiohttp&lt;/a&gt;, which
is licensed under Apache 2.0, He's very knowledgeable about it.
There were lots of interesting questions being asked at the tutorial, and he was
able to explain things clearly. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/matrixise"&gt;Stéphane Wirtel&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/webKnjaZ"&gt;Sviatoslav Sydorenko&lt;/a&gt; volunteered as our TA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D56v23uWAAIfE2Q.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="don-t-be-a-robot-build-the-bot"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't Be a Robot; Build the Bot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday after the keynote, I gave my talk titled &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_xdEAxLuj9Y"&gt;Don't Be a Robot; Build the Bot&lt;/a&gt;.
I loved giving that talk! It's a talk about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/miss-islington/"&gt;miss-islington&lt;/a&gt;!
I think more people should be building their own bots and automate! With
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gidgethub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/"&gt;gidgethub&lt;/a&gt; (Apache 2.0 licensed)
it is really easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="github-bots-are-one-honking-great-idea-let-s-do-more-of-those"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;GitHub bots are one honking great idea, let's do more of those!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sviatoslav and I hosted an open space on Sunday. We discussed more about GitHub bots,
building it for profit or for fun. Sviatoslav just made a new framework for building
GitHub Apps with Python 3.7, called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://octomachinery.dev/"&gt;octomachinery&lt;/a&gt;.
We also discussed about GitHub Actions, tried to make sense of it, e.g. what were
limitations, and what Actions would be useful. There is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://discuss.python.org/t/official-github-action-for-publishing-to-pypi/1061"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt;
for making an &amp;quot;official&amp;quot; GitHub Action for publishing to PyPI. Some people shared
ideas of what bots they'd like to see and build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One attendee (I think his name was Anurag Saxena(?)) said he'd like to
receive weekly updates of GitHub issues/PRs they
worked on, and to have it automatically sent to him as email or slack or
something. I think this is very interesting idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product placement: this can be accomplished with Zapier. You can create a
cron job that generates the summary (by utilizing GitHub Search API), and then use
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://zapier.com/apps/webhook/integrations"&gt;Webhook by Zapier&lt;/a&gt; to handle the
&amp;quot;send email/post a slack message&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="status-of-black-out"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Status of black-out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned my personal bot, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mariatta/black_out"&gt;black-out&lt;/a&gt;, in
my talk. Black-out is a GitHub bot that runs black (Python formatter) on incoming pull
requests. The first version of the webhook-based bot is open source and Apache 2.0
licensed. However, I wasn't happy with how it works, so I've been researching on
how to turn it into a GitHub App.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've made some progress with black-out GitHub App, I've implemented some of the features
I wanted for myself, but I'm still just experimenting and testing it out on my
own personal projects to really figure out what's the best workflow for the bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black-out GitHub App is still closed source, I have not put it up on GitHub yet.
After the talk, a few people, including &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/jezdez"&gt;Jannis Leidel&lt;/a&gt;
from Mozilla, expressed interest in black-out, and wanted to know how they can help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the interest! I think I just need to find time and put it up on GitHub
so we can all collaborate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="aiohttp-bot"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;aiohttp bot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aiohttp needs a bot just like miss-islington, for backporting, and Andrew Svetlov
had talked to me about this since early last year. (and Ansible needs their own
backport bot too). To help with this, we've been working to make &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pypi.org/project/cherry-picker/"&gt;cherry-picker.py&lt;/a&gt; customizable. I've offered to help
build this bot for aiohttp, and the easiest is a webhook-based bot, just like
miss-islington. However Sviatoslav disagrees. He prefers for it to be a GitHub
App that can be easily installed by other projects. While I like the GitHub App
idea, for reusability, I also think that each projects might have different workflow
for backporting, so we'll end up having to support &amp;quot;configuring the bot&amp;quot;, which is
a boring activity for me. I'll be thinking more about this, but my thinking right
now is to build it as a personal bot for aiohttp; not a customizable bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mentored-sprint-for-diverse-beginners"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mentored Sprint for Diverse Beginners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday afternoon (4 hrs) I helped ran the mentored sprint for Diverse Beginners. This
is a group effort with Tania Allard, Nina Zakharenko, and Nikoleta Glynatsi. We have
a room full of 70 new aspiring open source contributors, and about 30 mentors
from 11 different open source projects (like CPython, CircuitPython, TensorFlow,
etc) I think it was great success! The projects and mentors were tasked with
coming up with at least 5 beginner friendly issues, so they came prepared. Lots
of people with diverse background made their first pull requests at the sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that surprised me, was such great turnout! I've organized lots of
events and meetups, and we usually expect about 60% people will actually show up.
But for this event, &lt;strong&gt;EVERYBODY&lt;/strong&gt; showed up! Room was completely full!! (103 pax capacity)
We even had to turn away many people who wanted to walk-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://photos.app.goo.gl/YRJD9tkQSHZBzFcB9" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynotes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Keynotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to see pretty much all of the keynotes, except for Jessica McKellar's keynote.
Her keynote started late, and I was supposed to staff Zapier's booth at the same
time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sha's talk was very inspiring and emotional. I'm glad I was able to watch the
talk in person. I was going to suggest people to catch his talk, but unfortunately
there was no recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/8dDp-UHBJ_A"&gt;Steering council plenary session&lt;/a&gt;
moderated by Ewa Jodlowska. (there was mention about PEP 581!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pycascades"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyCascades&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D50oSeaXkAEb-uv.jpg:large" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday I met up with several PyCascades organizers and we discussed the planning of
next year's conference. We're still scouting venues in Portland, and figuring out
how to best divide tasks among the organizers. Eric Holscher will be co-chairing,
along with Esti. Somehow during that meeting, I became the next PyCascades
Diversity Chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pyladies"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyLadies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D56C8oTX4AESrtq.jpg:large" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(image from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/loooorenanicole/status/1125485680216485888"&gt;Lorena Mesa on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday I attended a meeting with other PyLadies organizers from all over the world.
We shared notes about organizing and leading our own local chapters. We learned that
the challenges faced by PyLadies in different parts of the world are different. We
talked about how the current representation of PyLadies isn't very diverse (represented
by people in North America) whereas members of Python community and PyLadies are coming
from all over the world. We talked about ideas on how PyLadies can be better. We
discussed the governance of PyLadies, and decided to do a monthly PyLadies organizers
meeting. Elaine and I volunteered to take over managing info at pyladies email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dep-9"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DEP 9&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into Andrew Godwin who is a Django Core Developer. I got to ask him about
Django and asyncio. During the aiohttp tutorial, someone had asked about aiohttp
and ORM. Andrew Svetlov mentioned that it is a low priority for aiohttp, and so
I wondered what is Django's stance on this. Andrew (Godwin) shared his plan about
async-capable django. I guess he was talking about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/andrewgodwin/status/1126328701593866240"&gt;DEP 9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="language-summit-retro-and-the-inspiration-for-black"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Language Summit retro, and the inspiration for black&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met with Łukasz Langa to celebrate success of running our first language summit.
We had informal retros, and started thinking about how to put the next year's event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got to ask him where the inspiration for black came from. He described
frustration with other auto-formatter, how it does not provide consistent
output (same file reformatted twice would give different result). After months
of frustration, he decided to make his own auto-formatter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D55tCx_W0AAT3tF.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="f-string-debug-mode"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;F-string Debug Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I had to give away all of my new f-string stickers to Eric V. Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric showed me a demo of debug mode for f-string. It adds the &lt;cite&gt;=&lt;/cite&gt; to the f-string
expression. I recalled we had this discussion with both Eric and Larry Hastings back during core Python sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
foo=5 print(f&amp;quot;{foo=}&amp;quot;)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;would print:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
foo=5
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then the PR has been merged, and now we need to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bugs.python.org/issue36858"&gt;write the documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D551XvfW4AImG49.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="people"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;People&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got to meet in person with people I've interacted online a lot, like:
Tania Allard, Cheryl Sabella, Anthony Shaw, Sviatoslav Sydorenko, Elizaaveta Shashkova,
and many more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D56eogZW0AAUZat.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="coc-incidents"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CoC Incidents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the conference, it was brought to my attention about several CoC incidents
that occurred in various communities I belong to. These issues are being dealt
with, and I've also talked to PyCon incident response team members where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ice-cream-selfie"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ice Cream Selfie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had ice cream sandwich from Cathy's Gourmet Ice Cream Sandwiches, courtesy of Tania and Nina 🍨😝🤳🏻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D568l3_WsAE3pF7.jpg:large" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pynutella"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyNutella&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyNutella, a.k.a that thing where Mariatta asks her friends who are coming to
PyCon to bring her Nutella from Europe, yeah that happened. Thanks to Christian
Heimes for the very special Nutella. My kids were mind blown to see them. Also
thanks to Stéphane Wirtel for a really big jar of Nutella from Belgium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5l36DKW4AAsgKP.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pierogicon"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PierogiCon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Ossowski, Jeff Triplett and I went back to Sokolowski's University Inn for the
second PierogiCon, and we brought in a number of newbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net/vp/d67f75c6b92d5fe66cb81e3dc124e539/5D660D3C/t51.2885-15/sh0.08/e35/s640x640/59183211_108900943546171_9078212037958768043_n.jpg?_nc_ht=instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="selfie-sprint"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Selfie Sprint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was meaning to do one day of sprints, but after a full week full of activities,
I decided not to do any open source activities, and instead just go around
and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;vertical=default&amp;amp;q=mariatta%20%23selfiesprint&amp;amp;src=typd"&gt;take selfie with people I met&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed doing Selfie Sprint! I think I will do it again next year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D56wr4nW4AcVeL6.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5600r5WkAEDxQh.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="seafood"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Seafood&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to see my brother for dinner. We had really great spicy seafood at Boiling Seafood Crawfish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net/vp/21ef88439f3331f9aa4990f886749903/5D6E3634/t51.2885-15/sh0.08/e35/s750x750/57488426_1264143830402264_5360864775533430374_n.jpg?_nc_ht=instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="award"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Award&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the biggest highlight for me is receiving my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pyfound.blogspot.com/2019/02/the-north-star-of-pycascades-core.html"&gt;Community Service Award&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday.
Thank you Python community for this recognition! (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P4IfFLAX9hY"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/kER4UTkQthe-c5t2LPaI2rvXB_TeD_WJNN6eCIHO6PApKV8FDkx-zwJeOOIxNu3WMNIO3pA4pKaIT06kgJDXqXbUe2LCX5q2aJJlSes2MubaizIlxkprG2djfHcLP0VaAf-LxKoSTUKp-wNzSGXHGsfXJxZghnN-z2la2HC3fLM2qAHCe8hT02gpd50AvRZsboMCmd2oLtbWsaIn0FC6aiSKue9vYVQzcmh__RNqJcPDKFmX2TLNSkx5x9BxU4dFZZtSr3lBZw0Hg7gmFgNl0lyuBcONGueS3QyzUcrsS-ERX17kCv_pgRCxLKyuabXQZ4_6paRtVp67yNQhmRfJPbhmGk1JAFnEJBTVB2-bQacpibiMKv6biEi1kilGmQQRHjMkoMIFMKqqWfikm2LTEjtr78m2SkycWdxsyzCgk6Pjkw96H6nnFUsDzeS1N0pJh2dSglySPI0RicAKn-8CA_8whMPowyN5EvsE0LvKnIxZ0SwsHaND7WLMFbBzn3v5bJfuFG7PvyDdxyTyoq97ANw622C0qsOkiW8z3I6J-E4z0NH_1X7iHM7B-ciQr6MltZV0haRmuebGV_AsZoDPL3-i_g_okf7lqR5QPHCf1iJgGfl1R9HLe6xMqdjXBVz3lX_zccIiFhE27hjsLSgkIu_R0N3izYz5LWaGtWdwAEPkEArubAeW0yWTCs9a6Z6kEJ6j2D_1UoJESoDV16CfstBp0g=w1000-h1333-no" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="until-next-time"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Until next time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to include as many memories as I can into this post, but I'm unable to include
everything. 😥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon 2019 has been inspiring. I learned a lot about the community, and I cried
a lot too (the good cry).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you organizers, volunteers, sponsors, and all the wonderful Python community for these memories.
Let's do this again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌮&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="pep581"></category></entry><entry><title>Mariatta @ PyCon 2019</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/mariatta-pycon-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-30T14:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-30T14:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mariatta</name></author><id>tag:mariatta.ca,2019-04-30:/mariatta-pycon-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Cleveland last night for PyCon 2019! It'll be quite busy and jam-packed
event for me!! Looking forward to meet old friends and make new ones!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are my pre-planned PyCon activities. But I'm sure in actuality
I'll be even more busier for the unplanned ones! 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Cleveland last night for PyCon 2019! It'll be quite busy and jam-packed
event for me!! Looking forward to meet old friends and make new ones!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are my pre-planned PyCon activities. But I'm sure in actuality
I'll be even more busier for the unplanned ones! 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2019/events/language-summit/"&gt;Python Language Summit&lt;/a&gt;,
co-chairing with Łukasz. I'm also going to present the topic about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0581/"&gt;PEP 581&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0588/"&gt;PEP 588&lt;/a&gt;. Followed by PyCon staff dinner. 😋&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;: Andrew Svetlov and I will be giving our tutorial together: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2019/schedule/presentation/68/"&gt;Hands-on
Intro to aiohttp&lt;/a&gt;. I'll
also be checking the expo hall for the opening reception.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;: I plan to attend the keynote, and then my own talk: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2019/schedule/presentation/218/"&gt;Don't Be a
Robot; Build the Bot&lt;/a&gt;
(Friday 10:50 a.m.–11:20 a.m. in Grand Ballroom B). I'll also be at Zapier's
booth (#713) from 3:45 - 4:30 PM. Come find me!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;: Attend the morning keynotes, and again at Zapier's booth (#713)
from 10:10 – 10:50 AM. PSF Member's lunch, and then the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mentored-sprint-for-diverse-beginners.readthedocs.io/"&gt;Mentored Sprint for
Diverse Beginners&lt;/a&gt;,
co-organized with Tania, Nina, and Nikoleta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;: Attend all the keynotes. Sviatoslav Sydorenko and I plan to do
an open space at 11 AM, with topic: &lt;strong&gt;GitHub Bots are one honking great idea --
let's do more of those! Let's talk about building GitHub Apps as a community&lt;/strong&gt;.
PyLadies lunch. Receive my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pyfound.blogspot.com/2019/02/the-north-star-of-pycascades-core.html"&gt;PSF Community Service&lt;/a&gt;
award. Dinner with my brother. This might be the last time in many years
before I'll get to see him again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;: Sprint! Probably try to catch up with all the things I've been missing
out since I went OOOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;: Go home!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ice-cream-selfie"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ice Cream Selfie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So unlike me, I have not decided where to go for &lt;a class="reference external" href="../pages/ice-cream-selfie.html"&gt;Ice Cream Selfie&lt;/a&gt;!!
😱 Last year I went to &lt;a class="reference external" href="../ics-pyconus-2018.html"&gt;Mitchell's Homemade Ice Cream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="sprint"></category><category term="pep581"></category></entry><entry><title>PyCon 2018</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/pycon-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-19T14:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-19T14:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mariatta</name></author><id>tag:mariatta.ca,2018-05-19:/pycon-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was at PyCon from May 9 - May 15. It's my fourth PyCon US, and has been very
special to me in many ways. (Also my busiest yet!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-badge.jpg" style="width: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="representing-zapier"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Representing Zapier&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Zapier for fully supporting my trip to PyCon, and for allowing me to
take the time away from work …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was at PyCon from May 9 - May 15. It's my fourth PyCon US, and has been very
special to me in many ways. (Also my busiest yet!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-badge.jpg" style="width: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="representing-zapier"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Representing Zapier&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Zapier for fully supporting my trip to PyCon, and for allowing me to
take the time away from work for more than a week. The significance of this, for
me personally, is that for the first time I didn't need to apply for financial
aid in order to attend PyCon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Zapier's support, I was able to stay for two days of sprints. It means
I get to contribute for open source for &lt;strong&gt;two full days&lt;/strong&gt;! 😆🌮&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="python-language-summit"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Python Language Summit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended the Python Language Summit for the second year. This time I presented
two topics. I had planned to do a lightning talk too, but by end of the day
I was too exhausted, so no lightning talk from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The language summit was open to Python core developers, and by invitation only.
There was no recording, however there will be an article by Jake Edge from LWN.
I presented two talk topics at the language summit. I'll leave you in suspense
as you await the LWN article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little side anecdote, when I first became a Python Core Developer last year,
a couple core devs and a BDFL each told me about the language summit. And each
one of them &lt;strong&gt;warned&lt;/strong&gt; me of a certain &lt;em&gt;incident&lt;/em&gt; happened at the language summit in
the past. To protect the identity and the integrity of the folks involved, I won't
say what the incident was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the year, I kept hearing of the same incident mentioned by several
other core devs. So I came to think of it as an urban legend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might have been two new urban legends born at Python Language
Summit 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="tutorial"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tutorial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/ZwvjtCjimiw"&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; at PyCon. I think it went quite well.
I definitely can be a better instructor next time, but I believe the attendees had
fun and learned many new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to thank my friends for coming and helping out at my tutorial. Many attendees
faced technical difficulties, and I would not have been able to attend to them
one by one. Really, it would not have gone as well without their help!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So thank you friends: Jane Williams, Matt Davis, Ned Deily, Victor Stinner,
Stéphane Wirtel, Eric V. Smith, Christian Heimes. You're all the best!
Thanks Carol Willing and Guido van Rossum for dropping by, and special thanks
Brett Cannon for the cameo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="talks"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/hhj7eb6TrtI"&gt;What is a Python Core Developer&lt;/a&gt;.
Poured my heart out, and felt really good afterwards. Thank you
everyone who came to my talk, (and for the standing ovation 🙇🏻‍♀️).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only managed to go to a several keynotes and talks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ITksU31c1WY"&gt;Dan Callahan's Keynote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=2935&amp;amp;v=tzFWz5fiVKU"&gt;Brett Cannon's Keynote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/3kta4GB3PAw"&gt;Catherine Devlin's Keynote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anna Ossowski: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/GmbaKdd6o6A"&gt;Flourishing FLOSS: Making Your Project Successful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christopher Neugebauer, Josh Simmons, Sam Kitajima-Kimbrel: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/C7ZhMnfUKIA"&gt;How we designed an inclusivity-first conference on a shoestring budget and short timeline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ned Batchelder: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/duvZ-2UK0fc"&gt;Big-O: How Code Slows as Data Grows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="sprint"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sprint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt quite productive during the sprint days!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of two days I made these contributions to open source:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created python/miss-islington &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/miss-islington/issues/88"&gt;PR #88&lt;/a&gt;:
Assign the failed PR to be backported to the core dev who merged it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewed and merged python/core-workflow &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/core-workflow/pull/238"&gt;PR #238&lt;/a&gt;:
Change single quotes to double quotes in get_author_info_from_short_sha to fix error in Windows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewed and merged python/devguide &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/devguide/pull/363"&gt;PR #363&lt;/a&gt;:
fix: fixed typo in the setup dev guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewed and merged python/cpython &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/cpython/pull/6609"&gt;PR #6609&lt;/a&gt;:
bpo-22069: Flush is implied also when write contains a carriage return&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewed python/cpython &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/cpython/pull/142"&gt;PR #142&lt;/a&gt;:
bpo-1025395: Fix email.utils.parseaddr to handle multiple hops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewed python/cpython &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/cpython/pull/6883"&gt;PR #6883&lt;/a&gt;
bpo-21475: Support the Sitemap extension in robotparser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created pycqa/pylint &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCQA/pylint/pull/2091"&gt;PR #2091&lt;/a&gt;:
Add a new check: &lt;cite&gt;logging-fstring-interpolation&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created pycqa/pylint &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/PyCQA/pylint/pull/2092"&gt;PR #2092&lt;/a&gt;:
Fix weird indentation in contributing guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created python/devguide &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/devguide/pull/362"&gt;PR #362&lt;/a&gt;:
Add link to zulipchat in communications page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Released &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pypi.org/project/cherry-picker/"&gt;cherry_picker v1.1.1&lt;/a&gt; to PyPI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussed the documentation for PEP 557 with Eric V. Smith and Ned Deily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I slacked off too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still found time to chat and gossip with other folks during the sprint days.
Thanks Ned Batchelder, Anna Ossowski, Jeff Triplett, Ernest W. Durbin III, and Guido
van Rossum for being available and lending their ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="regret"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Regret&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had wanted to help writing the documentation for PEP 557, the dataclasses module.
In the end I was not able to help with anything. Thank you Eric V. Smith for
writing up the proper documentation. Check it out &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.python.org/3.7/library/dataclasses.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric also gave me a crash course of the dataclasses module. No better way to
learn about it from the creator himself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="rainbow-roses"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rainbow Roses&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ordered a dozen rainbow roses to be delivered to my hotel room. They're very
lovely. I think I will make this a new ritual. 🌹💐&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the roses didn't make it, that's why there are only eleven in the photo. 😛&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-rainbowroses.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="poison"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Poison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, I had 11 shots of tequila over the period of 7 days. Eric Holscher
started to make a comment about it and James Bond and martini... 🤐
&lt;em&gt;I'm much less exciting than James Bond!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At dinner one evening with Victor and Guido, I didn't see tequila on the menu.
So we ended up with this cute drink that has only 12% alcohol. 😭&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-cutedrink.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wat"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wat?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave Beazley included &lt;cite&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;F&amp;quot;Yes!&amp;quot;&lt;/cite&gt; in his &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/loooorenanicole/status/995343478015102976"&gt;talk slides&lt;/a&gt;.
I didn't realize that he'd been reading my tweets. 🤭&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number of people who proudly wore their PyCascades t-shirt at PyCon truly amazed me.
Thank you!!!
🙇🏻‍♀️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the folks who said hi and told me that they know me by reputation...
🙇🏻‍♀🙇🏻‍♀🙇🏻‍♀🙇🏻‍♀&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photos"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other favorite memories from PyCon 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;The dessert at PyLadies lunch (on Mother's Day).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-pyladieslunch.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;PyCascades founders, 4 out of 6: Sebastian Vetter, Don Sheu, Eric Holscher, and myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-pycascades.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Met up with my brother and we ate lots of seafood at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="www.boilingseafoodcrawfishoh.com"&gt;Boiling Seafood Crawfish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-seafood.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;I didn't recognized my hero at first (never met him in person until PyCon), but he
recognized me. 🙈&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-hero.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Python Language Summit chairs handover/initiation meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-languagesummitchairs.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;My luggage was searched by the TSA. 🛃 #PyNutella&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/pycon2018-pynutella.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="until-next-time"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Until next time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to include as many memories as I can into this post, but I'm unable to include
everything. 😥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to chat and met with many many more people: all the Python Core Developers,
Python BDFL, open source project maintainers, PyLadies members, speakers, and various members
of this community. It's been inspiring and I learned a lot from all of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon 2018 had been very very busy, intense, special, and lovely. Thank
you organizers, volunteers, sponsors, and all the wonderful Python community for these memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌮&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="sprint"></category></entry></feed>