<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>mariatta.ca - pep581</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://mariatta.ca/feeds/pep581.tag.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://mariatta.ca/</id><updated>2019-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Weekly Update, July 8, 2019</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/weekly-update-july-8-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mariatta</name></author><id>tag:mariatta.ca,2019-07-08:/weekly-update-july-8-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This has started to become more like bi-weekly updates. 🤷🏻‍♀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well there was Canada Day stat holiday last weekend. My kids are out of school
for the summer, so I've been spending more time with them at instead of on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning about GraphQL, wrote a few lines of …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This has started to become more like bi-weekly updates. 🤷🏻‍♀️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well there was Canada Day stat holiday last weekend. My kids are out of school
for the summer, so I've been spending more time with them at instead of on the computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning about GraphQL, wrote a few lines of JS codes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researching other ways to run django management commands from admin. Came across the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pypi.org/project/django-admincommand/"&gt;django-admincommand&lt;/a&gt; package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other django-related work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some code reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployed to prod a few times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Career growth discussion with my manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="python-and-the-community"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Python and the community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://blog.jetbrains.com/pycharm/2019/06/webinar-recording-build-a-github-bot-with-mariatta-wijaya/"&gt;webinar with PyCharm&lt;/a&gt;!
I got to talk a bit about contributing to Python, and I also get to show how
you can automate your GitHub work with Zapier. Check it out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a couple new &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mariatta.ca/pages/about.html"&gt;GitHub sponsors&lt;/a&gt;
in the 🍪 tier. ❤️ Thank you! That brings it to 22 sponsors! You too can &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/users/Mariatta/sponsorship"&gt;sponsor
me on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for as little as $5/month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helped with the setup of PyLadies Monrovia (Liberia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created more PyLadies Slack-bots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sent an update about PEP 581 to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mail.python.org/archives/list/python-dev&amp;#64;python.org/thread/WXXY5RY5UV6DGBKANMHCGOW4UIKXVZ6S/"&gt;python-dev&lt;/a&gt;,
outlining the risks and downsides of GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued working on aiohttp-bot. I created &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/aio-libs/aiohttp-bot/pull/2"&gt;a PR&lt;/a&gt;,
but I still need to write more unit tests. Also, I found a bug with black-out. 😟&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some back and forth email communications with GitHub Support team and Ewa Jodlowska,
to get the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://discuss.python.org/t/proposal-create-bug-triage-team-on-github/992"&gt;Triagers role enabled for CPython&lt;/a&gt;.
The Python org on GitHub is now a non-profit organization, and we're in the Teams plan.
Thanks to Ewa and GitHub for all the help! For the next steps, you can check out
the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/core-workflow/projects/3"&gt;project in core-workflow GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="etc"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;etc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Celebrated Canada Day 🇨🇦&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;We handed over the keys to our old home to the new owners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Took the kids to the circus 🎪 I think the performers are pretty talented!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D-_G1F1UcAAD2JW.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Tried cooking gamjatang. It's ok but still not as good as I expected. Gotta try again
next time with different recipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net/vp/d3ad12039c9b36aa254f283d34b5200c/5DC5C4F8/t51.2885-15/sh0.08/e35/s750x750/65174140_462436261182546_4595852931976870381_n.jpg?_nc_ht=instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Our kids just started learning to bike on two wheels! They're making great
progress and we've been practising in the neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p class="first"&gt;Started scheming our next annual family vacation. We've been going to Cancún for
the last 3 family vacations. This time we'll be doing something else, but still in the
Caribbean. It's going to be FUN!! 😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="pep581"></category></entry><entry><title>Mariatta @ PyCon 2019 Recap</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/mariatta-pycon-2019-recap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mariatta</name></author><id>tag:mariatta.ca,2019-05-15:/mariatta-pycon-2019-recap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was at PyCon from April 29 - May 7. It's my fifth PyCon US. It's been a memorable
and, I kept busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5fCBZxXsAAnVU3.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a number of pre-planned activities for PyCon, like running the language
summit, giving talks, tutorial, etc. Thought I'll share a quick summary of how
they all …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was at PyCon from April 29 - May 7. It's my fifth PyCon US. It's been a memorable
and, I kept busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5fCBZxXsAAnVU3.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a number of pre-planned activities for PyCon, like running the language
summit, giving talks, tutorial, etc. Thought I'll share a quick summary of how
they all went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="zapier-pycon-2019"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Zapier &amp;#64; PyCon 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D52HmedWsAAr3D2.jpg:medium" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm one of 14 Zapiens at PyCon 2019. I staffed Zapier's booth on Friday and Saturday.
We had socks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="python-language-summit-2019"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Python Language Summit 2019&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The language summit was a success. First of all, we were able to stay somewhat
on time, which I'm personally quite happy about. Other thing to be proud of,
it was the most diverse audience I've seen. Our audience consists of, not just long-time
Python core developers, but also new contributors as well as members from
the wider Python ecosystem, such as from Twisted, Django, and BeeWare project.
We had talks about circuit Python, team communication, and mentorship. I personally
think all the talks were very interesting and refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've invited A. Jesse Jiryu Davis to cover the event. You can see his posts
at The PSF's &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pyfound.blogspot.com/2019/05/the-2019-python-language-summit.html"&gt;official blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We forgot to take a group photo after the summit!! 😱 but we had a group photo
with PyCon staff ... (image from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/pystar/status/1123782745585483776"&gt;PyCon's twitter account&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5hQscyW0AEIjUs.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pep-581"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PEP 581&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the topic of discussion was &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0581/"&gt;PEP 581&lt;/a&gt;.
Since Jesse is writing up the post about it, I won't duplicate the effort.
But you can see &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://speakerdeck.com/mariatta/pep-581"&gt;my slides here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd really like to see us making progress with this before the next Python
Language Summit. There were lots of action items, and things we still need
to figure out, but those will be addressed in &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0588/"&gt;PEP 588&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to update PEP 588 with the items raised during the language summit,
I really haven't had much time to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="hands-on-intro-to-aiohttp"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hands-on Intro to aiohttp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Svetlov and I gave a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us-pycon-2019-tutorial.readthedocs.io/"&gt;beginner tutorial to aiohttp&lt;/a&gt;.
Our tutorial material is available online, and licensed under CC-BY-SA 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew is the maintainer of &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://docs.aiohttp.org/en/stable/"&gt;aiohttp&lt;/a&gt;, which
is licensed under Apache 2.0, He's very knowledgeable about it.
There were lots of interesting questions being asked at the tutorial, and he was
able to explain things clearly. &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/matrixise"&gt;Stéphane Wirtel&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/webKnjaZ"&gt;Sviatoslav Sydorenko&lt;/a&gt; volunteered as our TA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D56v23uWAAIfE2Q.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="don-t-be-a-robot-build-the-bot"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Don't Be a Robot; Build the Bot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday after the keynote, I gave my talk titled &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_xdEAxLuj9Y"&gt;Don't Be a Robot; Build the Bot&lt;/a&gt;.
I loved giving that talk! It's a talk about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/miss-islington/"&gt;miss-islington&lt;/a&gt;!
I think more people should be building their own bots and automate! With
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gidgethub.readthedocs.io/en/latest/"&gt;gidgethub&lt;/a&gt; (Apache 2.0 licensed)
it is really easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="github-bots-are-one-honking-great-idea-let-s-do-more-of-those"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;GitHub bots are one honking great idea, let's do more of those!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sviatoslav and I hosted an open space on Sunday. We discussed more about GitHub bots,
building it for profit or for fun. Sviatoslav just made a new framework for building
GitHub Apps with Python 3.7, called &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://octomachinery.dev/"&gt;octomachinery&lt;/a&gt;.
We also discussed about GitHub Actions, tried to make sense of it, e.g. what were
limitations, and what Actions would be useful. There is a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://discuss.python.org/t/official-github-action-for-publishing-to-pypi/1061"&gt;proposal&lt;/a&gt;
for making an &amp;quot;official&amp;quot; GitHub Action for publishing to PyPI. Some people shared
ideas of what bots they'd like to see and build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One attendee (I think his name was Anurag Saxena(?)) said he'd like to
receive weekly updates of GitHub issues/PRs they
worked on, and to have it automatically sent to him as email or slack or
something. I think this is very interesting idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product placement: this can be accomplished with Zapier. You can create a
cron job that generates the summary (by utilizing GitHub Search API), and then use
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://zapier.com/apps/webhook/integrations"&gt;Webhook by Zapier&lt;/a&gt; to handle the
&amp;quot;send email/post a slack message&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="status-of-black-out"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Status of black-out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned my personal bot, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/mariatta/black_out"&gt;black-out&lt;/a&gt;, in
my talk. Black-out is a GitHub bot that runs black (Python formatter) on incoming pull
requests. The first version of the webhook-based bot is open source and Apache 2.0
licensed. However, I wasn't happy with how it works, so I've been researching on
how to turn it into a GitHub App.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've made some progress with black-out GitHub App, I've implemented some of the features
I wanted for myself, but I'm still just experimenting and testing it out on my
own personal projects to really figure out what's the best workflow for the bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black-out GitHub App is still closed source, I have not put it up on GitHub yet.
After the talk, a few people, including &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/jezdez"&gt;Jannis Leidel&lt;/a&gt;
from Mozilla, expressed interest in black-out, and wanted to know how they can help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the interest! I think I just need to find time and put it up on GitHub
so we can all collaborate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="aiohttp-bot"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;aiohttp bot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aiohttp needs a bot just like miss-islington, for backporting, and Andrew Svetlov
had talked to me about this since early last year. (and Ansible needs their own
backport bot too). To help with this, we've been working to make &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pypi.org/project/cherry-picker/"&gt;cherry-picker.py&lt;/a&gt; customizable. I've offered to help
build this bot for aiohttp, and the easiest is a webhook-based bot, just like
miss-islington. However Sviatoslav disagrees. He prefers for it to be a GitHub
App that can be easily installed by other projects. While I like the GitHub App
idea, for reusability, I also think that each projects might have different workflow
for backporting, so we'll end up having to support &amp;quot;configuring the bot&amp;quot;, which is
a boring activity for me. I'll be thinking more about this, but my thinking right
now is to build it as a personal bot for aiohttp; not a customizable bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="mentored-sprint-for-diverse-beginners"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mentored Sprint for Diverse Beginners&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday afternoon (4 hrs) I helped ran the mentored sprint for Diverse Beginners. This
is a group effort with Tania Allard, Nina Zakharenko, and Nikoleta Glynatsi. We have
a room full of 70 new aspiring open source contributors, and about 30 mentors
from 11 different open source projects (like CPython, CircuitPython, TensorFlow,
etc) I think it was great success! The projects and mentors were tasked with
coming up with at least 5 beginner friendly issues, so they came prepared. Lots
of people with diverse background made their first pull requests at the sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that surprised me, was such great turnout! I've organized lots of
events and meetups, and we usually expect about 60% people will actually show up.
But for this event, &lt;strong&gt;EVERYBODY&lt;/strong&gt; showed up! Room was completely full!! (103 pax capacity)
We even had to turn away many people who wanted to walk-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://photos.app.goo.gl/YRJD9tkQSHZBzFcB9" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="keynotes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Keynotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to see pretty much all of the keynotes, except for Jessica McKellar's keynote.
Her keynote started late, and I was supposed to staff Zapier's booth at the same
time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sha's talk was very inspiring and emotional. I'm glad I was able to watch the
talk in person. I was going to suggest people to catch his talk, but unfortunately
there was no recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtu.be/8dDp-UHBJ_A"&gt;Steering council plenary session&lt;/a&gt;
moderated by Ewa Jodlowska. (there was mention about PEP 581!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pycascades"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyCascades&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D50oSeaXkAEb-uv.jpg:large" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday I met up with several PyCascades organizers and we discussed the planning of
next year's conference. We're still scouting venues in Portland, and figuring out
how to best divide tasks among the organizers. Eric Holscher will be co-chairing,
along with Esti. Somehow during that meeting, I became the next PyCascades
Diversity Chair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pyladies"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyLadies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D56C8oTX4AESrtq.jpg:large" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(image from &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/loooorenanicole/status/1125485680216485888"&gt;Lorena Mesa on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday I attended a meeting with other PyLadies organizers from all over the world.
We shared notes about organizing and leading our own local chapters. We learned that
the challenges faced by PyLadies in different parts of the world are different. We
talked about how the current representation of PyLadies isn't very diverse (represented
by people in North America) whereas members of Python community and PyLadies are coming
from all over the world. We talked about ideas on how PyLadies can be better. We
discussed the governance of PyLadies, and decided to do a monthly PyLadies organizers
meeting. Elaine and I volunteered to take over managing info at pyladies email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="dep-9"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DEP 9&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran into Andrew Godwin who is a Django Core Developer. I got to ask him about
Django and asyncio. During the aiohttp tutorial, someone had asked about aiohttp
and ORM. Andrew Svetlov mentioned that it is a low priority for aiohttp, and so
I wondered what is Django's stance on this. Andrew (Godwin) shared his plan about
async-capable django. I guess he was talking about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/andrewgodwin/status/1126328701593866240"&gt;DEP 9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="language-summit-retro-and-the-inspiration-for-black"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Language Summit retro, and the inspiration for black&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met with Łukasz Langa to celebrate success of running our first language summit.
We had informal retros, and started thinking about how to put the next year's event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got to ask him where the inspiration for black came from. He described
frustration with other auto-formatter, how it does not provide consistent
output (same file reformatted twice would give different result). After months
of frustration, he decided to make his own auto-formatter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D55tCx_W0AAT3tF.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="f-string-debug-mode"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;F-string Debug Mode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I had to give away all of my new f-string stickers to Eric V. Smith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eric showed me a demo of debug mode for f-string. It adds the &lt;cite&gt;=&lt;/cite&gt; to the f-string
expression. I recalled we had this discussion with both Eric and Larry Hastings back during core Python sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
foo=5 print(f&amp;quot;{foo=}&amp;quot;)
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;would print:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="literal-block"&gt;
foo=5
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then the PR has been merged, and now we need to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://bugs.python.org/issue36858"&gt;write the documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D551XvfW4AImG49.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="people"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;People&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got to meet in person with people I've interacted online a lot, like:
Tania Allard, Cheryl Sabella, Anthony Shaw, Sviatoslav Sydorenko, Elizaaveta Shashkova,
and many more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D56eogZW0AAUZat.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="coc-incidents"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CoC Incidents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the conference, it was brought to my attention about several CoC incidents
that occurred in various communities I belong to. These issues are being dealt
with, and I've also talked to PyCon incident response team members where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ice-cream-selfie"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ice Cream Selfie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had ice cream sandwich from Cathy's Gourmet Ice Cream Sandwiches, courtesy of Tania and Nina 🍨😝🤳🏻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D568l3_WsAE3pF7.jpg:large" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pynutella"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PyNutella&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyNutella, a.k.a that thing where Mariatta asks her friends who are coming to
PyCon to bring her Nutella from Europe, yeah that happened. Thanks to Christian
Heimes for the very special Nutella. My kids were mind blown to see them. Also
thanks to Stéphane Wirtel for a really big jar of Nutella from Belgium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5l36DKW4AAsgKP.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pierogicon"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PierogiCon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anna Ossowski, Jeff Triplett and I went back to Sokolowski's University Inn for the
second PierogiCon, and we brought in a number of newbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net/vp/d67f75c6b92d5fe66cb81e3dc124e539/5D660D3C/t51.2885-15/sh0.08/e35/s640x640/59183211_108900943546171_9078212037958768043_n.jpg?_nc_ht=instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="selfie-sprint"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Selfie Sprint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was meaning to do one day of sprints, but after a full week full of activities,
I decided not to do any open source activities, and instead just go around
and &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;vertical=default&amp;amp;q=mariatta%20%23selfiesprint&amp;amp;src=typd"&gt;take selfie with people I met&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed doing Selfie Sprint! I think I will do it again next year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D56wr4nW4AcVeL6.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/D5600r5WkAEDxQh.jpg" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="seafood"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Seafood&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to see my brother for dinner. We had really great spicy seafood at Boiling Seafood Crawfish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net/vp/21ef88439f3331f9aa4990f886749903/5D6E3634/t51.2885-15/sh0.08/e35/s750x750/57488426_1264143830402264_5360864775533430374_n.jpg?_nc_ht=instagram.fyvr4-1.fna.fbcdn.net" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="award"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Award&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the biggest highlight for me is receiving my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pyfound.blogspot.com/2019/02/the-north-star-of-pycascades-core.html"&gt;Community Service Award&lt;/a&gt; on Sunday.
Thank you Python community for this recognition! (&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P4IfFLAX9hY"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/kER4UTkQthe-c5t2LPaI2rvXB_TeD_WJNN6eCIHO6PApKV8FDkx-zwJeOOIxNu3WMNIO3pA4pKaIT06kgJDXqXbUe2LCX5q2aJJlSes2MubaizIlxkprG2djfHcLP0VaAf-LxKoSTUKp-wNzSGXHGsfXJxZghnN-z2la2HC3fLM2qAHCe8hT02gpd50AvRZsboMCmd2oLtbWsaIn0FC6aiSKue9vYVQzcmh__RNqJcPDKFmX2TLNSkx5x9BxU4dFZZtSr3lBZw0Hg7gmFgNl0lyuBcONGueS3QyzUcrsS-ERX17kCv_pgRCxLKyuabXQZ4_6paRtVp67yNQhmRfJPbhmGk1JAFnEJBTVB2-bQacpibiMKv6biEi1kilGmQQRHjMkoMIFMKqqWfikm2LTEjtr78m2SkycWdxsyzCgk6Pjkw96H6nnFUsDzeS1N0pJh2dSglySPI0RicAKn-8CA_8whMPowyN5EvsE0LvKnIxZ0SwsHaND7WLMFbBzn3v5bJfuFG7PvyDdxyTyoq97ANw622C0qsOkiW8z3I6J-E4z0NH_1X7iHM7B-ciQr6MltZV0haRmuebGV_AsZoDPL3-i_g_okf7lqR5QPHCf1iJgGfl1R9HLe6xMqdjXBVz3lX_zccIiFhE27hjsLSgkIu_R0N3izYz5LWaGtWdwAEPkEArubAeW0yWTCs9a6Z6kEJ6j2D_1UoJESoDV16CfstBp0g=w1000-h1333-no" style="width: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="until-next-time"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Until next time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to include as many memories as I can into this post, but I'm unable to include
everything. 😥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon 2019 has been inspiring. I learned a lot about the community, and I cried
a lot too (the good cry).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you organizers, volunteers, sponsors, and all the wonderful Python community for these memories.
Let's do this again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌮&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="pep581"></category></entry><entry><title>Mariatta @ PyCon 2019</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/mariatta-pycon-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-30T14:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-30T14:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mariatta</name></author><id>tag:mariatta.ca,2019-04-30:/mariatta-pycon-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Cleveland last night for PyCon 2019! It'll be quite busy and jam-packed
event for me!! Looking forward to meet old friends and make new ones!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are my pre-planned PyCon activities. But I'm sure in actuality
I'll be even more busier for the unplanned ones! 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday …&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Cleveland last night for PyCon 2019! It'll be quite busy and jam-packed
event for me!! Looking forward to meet old friends and make new ones!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are my pre-planned PyCon activities. But I'm sure in actuality
I'll be even more busier for the unplanned ones! 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2019/events/language-summit/"&gt;Python Language Summit&lt;/a&gt;,
co-chairing with Łukasz. I'm also going to present the topic about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0581/"&gt;PEP 581&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0588/"&gt;PEP 588&lt;/a&gt;. Followed by PyCon staff dinner. 😋&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;: Andrew Svetlov and I will be giving our tutorial together: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2019/schedule/presentation/68/"&gt;Hands-on
Intro to aiohttp&lt;/a&gt;. I'll
also be checking the expo hall for the opening reception.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;: I plan to attend the keynote, and then my own talk: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://us.pycon.org/2019/schedule/presentation/218/"&gt;Don't Be a
Robot; Build the Bot&lt;/a&gt;
(Friday 10:50 a.m.–11:20 a.m. in Grand Ballroom B). I'll also be at Zapier's
booth (#713) from 3:45 - 4:30 PM. Come find me!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;: Attend the morning keynotes, and again at Zapier's booth (#713)
from 10:10 – 10:50 AM. PSF Member's lunch, and then the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mentored-sprint-for-diverse-beginners.readthedocs.io/"&gt;Mentored Sprint for
Diverse Beginners&lt;/a&gt;,
co-organized with Tania, Nina, and Nikoleta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;: Attend all the keynotes. Sviatoslav Sydorenko and I plan to do
an open space at 11 AM, with topic: &lt;strong&gt;GitHub Bots are one honking great idea --
let's do more of those! Let's talk about building GitHub Apps as a community&lt;/strong&gt;.
PyLadies lunch. Receive my &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pyfound.blogspot.com/2019/02/the-north-star-of-pycascades-core.html"&gt;PSF Community Service&lt;/a&gt;
award. Dinner with my brother. This might be the last time in many years
before I'll get to see him again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday&lt;/strong&gt;: Sprint! Probably try to catch up with all the things I've been missing
out since I went OOOS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt;: Go home!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="ice-cream-selfie"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ice Cream Selfie&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So unlike me, I have not decided where to go for &lt;a class="reference external" href="../pages/ice-cream-selfie.html"&gt;Ice Cream Selfie&lt;/a&gt;!!
😱 Last year I went to &lt;a class="reference external" href="../ics-pyconus-2018.html"&gt;Mitchell's Homemade Ice Cream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="PyCon"></category><category term="sprint"></category><category term="pep581"></category></entry><entry><title>Weekly Update, April 30, 2019</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/weekly-update-april-30-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Mariatta</name></author><id>tag:mariatta.ca,2019-04-30:/weekly-update-april-30-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short week, 3 days of work, but quite productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published my Zapier engineering blog post: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://zapier.com/engineering/zapier-at-pycon-2019/"&gt;Zapier at PyCon 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a couple PRs. One of it was about customizing Django Admin. The other is
for a new Zapier API endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="python-and-the-community"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Python and the community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave a preview of my …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short week, 3 days of work, but quite productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published my Zapier engineering blog post: &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://zapier.com/engineering/zapier-at-pycon-2019/"&gt;Zapier at PyCon 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made a couple PRs. One of it was about customizing Django Admin. The other is
for a new Zapier API endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="python-and-the-community"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Python and the community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave a preview of my PyCon tutorial at PyLadies Vancouver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some more administrative work for the mentored sprint and Python Language Summit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responded to comment about &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/peps/pull/1013#issuecomment-488160914"&gt;PEP 581&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="etc"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;etc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spent a couple days packing all of my earthly belongings into boxes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Saturday we moved to our new home!!!! It's not 1 Infinite Loop, but it is number 1!! 🥇&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img alt="" src="../img/number-one-home.jpg" style="width: 200px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="pep581"></category></entry><entry><title>Python Core Sprint 2018: Part Two</title><link href="https://mariatta.ca/core-sprint-2018-part-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-09-21T09:14:06-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-21T09:14:06-07:00</updated><author><name>Mariatta</name></author><id>tag:mariatta.ca,2018-09-21:/core-sprint-2018-part-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read up on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mariatta.ca/core-sprint-2018-part-1.html"&gt;Part one&lt;/a&gt; first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are additional discussions and projects that I got involved with during the
sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pep-581"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PEP 581&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0581/"&gt;PEP 581&lt;/a&gt; is a PEP I wrote about using
GitHub issues instead of Roundup as CPython's issue tracker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the sprint, I discussed this topic mainly with Ezio …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read up on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mariatta.ca/core-sprint-2018-part-1.html"&gt;Part one&lt;/a&gt; first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are additional discussions and projects that I got involved with during the
sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="pep-581"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PEP 581&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0581/"&gt;PEP 581&lt;/a&gt; is a PEP I wrote about using
GitHub issues instead of Roundup as CPython's issue tracker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the sprint, I discussed this topic mainly with Ezio Melotti, as well as
with a group of other core devs: Ned Deily, Kushal Das, Petr Viktorin, Pablo Galindo,
and one-on-one with Zachary Ware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks all of you who came and discussed this with me, I really appreciate your
input and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting back, my tone might have been unkind, impatient, and unempathetic during
certain parts of the group discussion, and I'm sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most other PEPs, the idea for this PEP did not go through rounds of
discussions over at python-ideas. And unlike other PEPs, I did not post this PEP
into python-dev after it has been written. It was my own choice. Instead, this idea
was discussed at Python Language Summit, as a thread at python-committers, and
I also chatted privately with a few other Python core developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ezio, who maintains Roundup for CPython, talked to various core devs individually
to get a sense whether people are warm to the idea of moving to GitHub. It seems
like people are postive about it, or at least not strongly opposing the idea,  but
we still need to iron out additional details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the concerns raised during the discussions with core devs at
the sprint:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if GitHub disappear suddenly?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize that my response to this question had been unkind, impatient,
unempathetic, and I'm sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My response was &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I don't care&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I really meant is, &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I don't believe GitHub will go away all that suddenly&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;,
and that is my personal opinion, and I know there are people who thinks otherwise,
and I respect the difference in opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the actual question needing actual answer is: &lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;What is our fail safe plan?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;.
This is something that the PEP needs to address. At the moment, we'll just going to get
daily backups of GitHub data. But eventually we will need a more concrete
plan and we will need to be able to easily spin up another issue tracker / repository
so Python world does not stop and people can continue
contributing and developing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this problem is not unique to CPython. Lack of fail-safe solution should
not blocking the PEP's acceptance, and should not stop us from using GitHub issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about current bug triage permission?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Roundup currently, we have a separate &amp;quot;bug triage&amp;quot; permission that is different
than the core developer / commit access. The bug triage permission allows them
to close and categorize issues on the issue tracker, but does not give the
permission to commit or merge pull requests to CPython.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bug triage permission is definitely valuable for the team. Historically,
we've been able to give this permission easily to people without much formality,
whereas giving commit access is not so trivial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We definitely need bug triage help, and the question is, how will this be managed
with GitHub?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple ideas. Donald Stufft commented in Zulip that we can give
people write access, invite them as team collaborators, this will allow them to
edit and close issues, but use the GitHub branch protection feature to restrict
pushing codes to only Python core developers. BTW, we have been using this
feature, just didn't quite realize it. Python &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;3.4&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;3.5&lt;/tt&gt; branches on GitHub
are currently &amp;quot;protected&amp;quot;, and only the release manager, Larry Hastings, can
push codes to those branches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what we can do is to invite the current bug triagers as collaborators for
CPython repository, give them that write access, and add branch protection
such that only Python core developers can push / commit into the active branches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another idea that came up while chatting with Zach, now that miss-islington
can automerge, maybe we let only miss-islington to merge and commit from now on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Nosy list&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Dower commented that one nice feature of the existing issue tracker is
the nosy list, where he can get notified only in issues he's interested in. For
example, if someone creates an issue with &amp;quot;Windows&amp;quot; component in the current issue
tracker, he and Zach will be automatically notified and added to the nosy list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is not yet similar functionality on GitHub. So we're going to build out a
bot that does this somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have started researching GitHub's &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://developer.github.com/v3/activity/notifications/"&gt;notification and subscription APIs&lt;/a&gt;, but I don't have
clear idea or solution to this problem yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Involve the Python Release manager in the transition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ned Deily, Release Manager for Python 3.6 and 3.7, reminded us that we will need
to include the release managers for any changes in our workflow and issue tracker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub can lower the barrier to contribute, but also makes it easier for people to submit unrelevant issues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some core devs were concerned that the ease of using GitHub can also mean easier
for people to use and abuse it for things other than discussing bugs and features of
Python. It means that we will need to spend more time into triaging issues, marking
things as off topic, duplicate, telling people to file their issue somewhere else,
and so on. I think this is a valid concern. But I think this is an existing problem
anyway, regardless of what issue tracker we use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been experimenting with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://gitmate.io/"&gt;GitMate.io&lt;/a&gt; myself.
One of Gitmate's ability is to identify if an issue is a duplicate of other previously
reported issues. GitMate is currently installed in devguide, core-workflow, and
miss-islington repos. I've seen it help several people, but sometimes it is not
so helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CoC enforcement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to have better and clearer policy on CoC enforcement for handling comments
on GitHub. I know that there is the PSF's CoC work group now, and Brett is part of that
group. I'm glad that there is some progress, and I look forward hearing more from the
CoC work group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="cla"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CLA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of CPython's workflow that could use an improvement is the way we
handle CLA (Contributor License Agreement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way it works, for every contribution and pull request you made to Python
(CPython, DevGuide, PEPs, core-workflow, and all the bots), you'll need to
sign the CLA before we can accept and merge the pull request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently several problems with this workflow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signing the CLA also requires creating an account in the bug tracker. So
people making pull requests on GitHub needs to go to bugs.python.org, create
an account, and then add in their GitHub username. While this makes sense
for contributors to CPython, there is really no reason for contributors to
DevGuide or cherry-picker to do this. It just slows down the process of
contributing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It requires manual work by members of The PSF (Ewa and Betsy) to check if the CLA
has been signed, and they have to manually update the record in bugs.python.org.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the CLA has been signed, the pull request does not get automatically
updated with this new information. Contributors used to have to ping a core
developer to update the label on the PR, and a core developer has to come back
to the PR and remove the label. This has gotten better recently, with the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://check-python-cla.herokuapp.com/"&gt;check-python-cla&lt;/a&gt; website. But it
still is somewhat manual process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It could take at least a day, sometimes more, for the CLA process to clear. It
blocks pull requests from being merged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It really would be nice if this whole process can be automated, not requires much
human involvement, and if it can be completed in seconds instead of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been discussing this issue with Brett since early this year. I've also
started a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mail.python.org/mm3/archives/list/core-workflow&amp;#64;python.org/thread/JBV3XJVD2DLDX5DY7TZEA6CO5YPNHJ2C/"&gt;couple threads&lt;/a&gt;
in core-workflow mailing list. Per Yury's suggestion, I've started looking into
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://cla-assistant.io/"&gt;cla-assistant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the sprint, I got to discuss this more with Brett on how to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal preference is actually use the hosted version of cla-assistant,
so we don't have to maintain it. (&lt;strong&gt;We&lt;/strong&gt; here really means only myself, Brett,
and Ernest).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People expressed concern that the system could go away quite suddenly, so
we're going to need to have some fail-safe mechanism if that ever happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the problem of &amp;quot;what if this goes away suddenly&amp;quot; is not be unique problem
to Python. I'm now actually curious to hear from other projects that use hosted
cla-assistant, and if they have their own backup plan in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chatted with Ernest, and he said it will be easy enough for us to host our
own instance of CLA assistant. Ernest has started looking into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several outstanding issues with cla-assistant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does it handle people who signed on behalf of an organization?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It allows us to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cla-assistant/cla-assistant#request-more-information-from-the-cla-signer"&gt;request more information from the CLA signer&lt;/a&gt;,
but when we export the data, the additional metada were not returned. It seems
like a bug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we get daily backups automatically? It seems like the only way to get the
backup is by going to the website, and click on a menu item that says &amp;quot;Export&amp;quot;.
Is there an API endpoint we can use, or do we need to build it ourselves?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we export out current signed CLAs from the bug tracker to cla-assistant?
Ezio had actually started working on getting me a &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;.csv&lt;/tt&gt; for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran out of time and energy to follow through with all of the above during the
sprint, so sadly we're still not yet using this new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Brett, Ernest, and Ezio for looking into this with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="fake-f-strings"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fake f-strings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I selfishly wanted Larry to &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/core-workflow/issues/283"&gt;drop Python 3.5 support&lt;/a&gt; in blurb. Blurb was
initially written with f-strings, but later on, all f-strings were replaced with
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/core-workflow/pull/146"&gt;str.format&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been quite disappointed about it since last year, and I know I actually
have better things to do than being sad about a tool so crucial for CPython does
not have any f-strings in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, Larry entertained my selfish request and came up with &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/python/core-workflow/pull/288"&gt;fake f-strings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll take it. Thanks Larry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="real-f-strings-and-asyncio"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Real f-strings and asyncio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until the sprint, I had never tried doing something like &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;f&amp;quot;{await&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="pre"&gt;somecoroutine()}&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;,
so I didn't know if it would even work. Since the creators and maintainers of
f-strings and asyncio are in the room, I thought I'll just ask them if it can work,
and I should get a quick firm &amp;quot;yes/no&amp;quot; answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was slight hesitation from core devs in answering such question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;It should work?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I think so?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Brett wrote us a small script to see if it will really work, with myself and
Eric V. Smith as witness. The result is, this works for Python 3.7+.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out later that it does not work in Python 3.6, but I don't actually know
the reason why. Something changed with how &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;await&lt;/tt&gt; works between 3.6 and 3.7?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🤷🏻‍♀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Yury &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/1st1/status/1042858310641152001"&gt;commented on twitter&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;yes, this needs Python 3.7+ to work. Before 3.7 async and await were not proper
keywords, so the interpreter did not recognize them in some contexts.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Yury! Now we have new reason to start using Python 3.7+!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="to-be-continued"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;To be continued&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be Part 3, &lt;em&gt;someday&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="Python"></category><category term="sprint"></category><category term="cla"></category><category term="pep581"></category></entry></feed>